Guide to the Photographer File circa 1882-2017, undated PR 50
New-York Historical Society
Photographer File
circa 1882-2017, undated
New-York Historical Society
PR 50
13 Linear feet in 14 boxes + 4 flat file
The collection is a file containing photographs, mainly of New York City, taken by notable photographers including Berenice Abbott; Lilyan Aloma; Joseph Aronberg; Alice Austen; Jim Beecher; Paul Bernius; Alice Boughton; Margaret Bourke-White; Rudy Burckhardt; Lawrence Cherney; William Cooper; Jeff Cowen; Melody D.Davis; Arnold Eagle; Joyce Edelman; Seymour Edelstein; Charlotte Fairchild; Harold Feinstein; Mark Feldstein; Steven Fenn; Geral Jude James Festa; Peter Fink; Andrew Garn; Lynn Gilbert; Keith Gould; Seth Greenwald; Serge Hambourg; Ben Heller; Evelyn Hofer; Steve Hoffman; Francis Benjamin Johnston; Raphael Kalmonoff; Karen Kent; Martin Leifer; Gina LeVay; Ann Littlejohn; Danny Lyon; Chris Mackey; Thomas McGovern; Neil Meyerhoff; Alexander Mikhailovich; Peter Nappi; Bob Newey; Dinanda Nooney; Clayton Price; Emery Reves-Biro; Orville Roberts; Laura Rosen; Fred Rosenberg; Thurman Rotan; James Rudnick; Marie Louise Russell; Arthur Sacks; Frederico Savini; Richard Schiffman; Marcia Sheer; Eve Stroh; Joan Vitale Strong; Leon Supraner; Donna Svennevik; Gilles Vauclaire; Wolf Von dem Bussche; Ray Waters; Richard Wilcox, John Wyatt; Paula Wright
Arrangement
The finding aid is organized alphabetically by photographer's name; photographs are housed by size.
Historical Note
The Photographer File is an artificial collection of photographs that have been acquired through donation or purchase from prominent photographers. Photographs in this collection were often acquired in small numbers or for exhibitions at The New-York Historical Society. Some of the photographs in this collection were included in The New-York Historical Society exhibit "Manhattan Now: 14 Photographers Look at the Form of the City" in 1974, or the 1981 exhibit "Manhattan Observed: Fourteen Photographers Look at New York, 1972-1981." The Photographer File has developed over the years as a collection to house photographs of New York, often by well-known New York photographers. While the file consists mostly of work from the 1930s through the present, photographs by some early portrait photographers, such as Alice Boughton, Frances Benjamin Johnson, Charlotte Fairchild, Underwood & Underwood, and William A. Cooper are also included.
Access Restrictions
For more information on making arrangements to consult the collection, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Most of the photographs within the Photographer File were purchased from or donated by the photographers, often for use in exhibitions. Larger gifts include the following: photographs by Alice Austen were a gift of Henry Marion Ward in 1942; Jim Beecher donated his photographs in 1986; Chris Mackey donated her photographs in 1983; Sy Edelstein donated his photographs in 1994; Wolf Von Dem Bussche's photographs were a gift of Mr. and Mrs. Timothy A. Eaton in 1997; Arthur Sacks donated his photographs in 1987; Paula Wright donated her 1964-1965 World's Fair photographs in 1993; 11 photographs by Joyce Edelman were donated by Deborah Edelman in 1992; Charles Schwartz donated photographs by a number of photographers in 2002, and Fred Rosenberg donated his photographs in 2004.
Scope and Content Note
The Photographer File dates primarily from 1930 through the present, but includes a few photographs by prominent photographers from as early as ca. 1882. The finding aid is arranged alphabetically by photographer's name; photographs are housed by size. Because of the varied nature of this collection, the photographs have been described more fully under each photographer's name in the folder listing. Researchers should be aware that in most cases the permission of the photographer is required for reproduction of images.
Included within this collection are photographs by Berenice Abbott; Lilyan Aloma; Joseph Aronberg; Alice Austen; Jim Beecher; Paul Bernius; Alice Boughton; Margaret Bourke-White; Rudy Burckhardt; Lawrence Cherney; William Cooper; Jeff Cowen; Melody D.Davis; Arnold Eagle; Joyce Edelman; Seymour Edelstein; Charlotte Fairchild; Harold Feinstein; Mark Feldstein; Steven Fenn; Gerald Jude James Festa; Peter Fink; Andrew Garn; Lynn Gilbert; Keith Gould; Seth Greenwald; Serge Hambourg; Ben Heller; Evelyn Hofer; Steve Hoffman; Francis Benjamin Johnston; Raphael Kalmonoff; Rivka Katvan; Karen Kent; Martin Leifer; Gina LeVay; Ann Littlejohn; Danny Lyon; Chris Mackey; Thomas McGovern; Neil Meyerhoff; Alexander Mikhailovich; Peter Nappi; Bob Newey; Dinanda Nooney; Clayton Price; Emery Reves-Biro; Orville Roberts; Laura Rosen; Fred Rosenberg; Thurman Rotan; James Rudnick; Marie Louise Russell; Arthur Sacks; Frederico Savini; Richard Schiffman; Marcia Sheer; Eve Stroh; Joan Vitale Strong; Leon Supraner; Donna Svennevik; Gilles Vauclaire; Wolf Von dem Bussche; Ray Waters; John Wyatt; Paula Wright. Prominent people portrayed in this collection include Bill Cunningham, David Dinkins, Nelson Mandela, Albert Einstein, Doc Cheatham, Henry James, Charles Dana Gibson, Billie Jean King.
Accruals
Additions to the collection are expected to occur from time to time, both for additional photographs and for photographs by photographers not presently represented in the collection. On the other hand, as has happened in the past, a curatorial decision may be made to transfer a particular photographer's work from this collection to a standalone collection of their own.
Separated Material
Photographs by the following have been removed to their own collections over time: Ruth Orkin (PR 190), Bill Aron (PR 192), Sidney Kerner (PR 193), Morris Huberland (PR 194), Harold Roth (PR 195), Lewis F. White (PR 196), Rhoda Galyn (PR 197), Robert Gambee (PR 198), Michael George (PR 199), David Sagarin (PR 200), Jan Staller (PR 201), Philip Trager (PR 202), Eadweard Muybridge (PR 205), William F. Winter (PR 206), Andreas Feininger (PR 207), Bill Cunningham (PR 307), Janelle Lynch (PR 344), Steven Harmon (PR 362), Ken Ratner (PR 373), Samuel Gottscho (PR 423), Bob Gore (PR 424).
Portraits.; New York (N.Y.) -- Description and travel.; Photographic prints.; Coasts -- New York (State); New York (N.Y.) -- Buildings, structures, etc.; Marine photography.; Costume -- United States.; Streets -- New York (State) -- New York.; Historic buildings -- New York (State) -- New York.; Aronberg, Joseph; Austin, Alice, 1866-1952; Bernstein, Leonard, 1918-1990; Beecher, Jim; Bernius, Paul; Reves-Biro, Emery, 1895-1975; Boughton, Alice, 1865-1943; Bourke-White, Margaret, 1904-1971; Burckhardt, Rudy; Cheatham, Doc -- Photographs.; Cherney, Lawrence (Photographer); Cooper, William (Photographer); Cowen, Jeff, 1966-; Cunningham, Bill, 1929-2016; Davis, Melody D., 1959-; Dinkins, David N. -- Photographs.; Eagle, Arnold; Edelman, Joyce Alexis, 1945-1991; Edelstein, Seymour; Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955 -- Photographs.; Fairchild, Charlotte; Fassbender, Adolf, 1884-1980; Feinstein, Harold; Feldstein, Mark, 1937-; Festa, Gerald Jude James; Fink, Peter, 1948-; Garn, Andrew; Gilbert, Lynn; Gibson, Charles Dana, 1867-1944 -- Photographs.; Goldfarb, Anders, 1954-; González, Alfred; Greenwald, Seth; Hambourg, Serge; Harmon, Stephen F., 1943-; Heller, Ben (Photographer); Hofer, Evelyn; Johnston, Frances Benjamin, 1864-1952; Kalmonoff, Raphael; Katvan, Rivka; Kent, Karen, 1941-; King, Billie Jean; Leifer, Martin, 1916-; Levine, James, 1943-; Littlejohn, Ann; Lyon, Danny; Mackey, Chris (Photographer); Mandela, Nelson, 1918-2013 -- Photographs.; Meyerhoff, Neil A., 1949-; Meyers, William, 1938-; Mikhailovich, Alexander; Moser, Lida; Nappi, Peter; Nooney, Dinanda; Price, Clayton J.; Robertson, Orville, 1959-; Rosen, Laura; Rosenberg, Fred (Photographer); Rotan, Thurman, 1903-1991; Rudnick, James (Photographer); Russell, Marie Louise, 1884-1946; Sacks, Arthur (Photographer); Savini, Frederico; Schiffman, Richard, 1952-; Sheer, Marcia, 1916-1989; Stroh, Eve, 1917-; Strong, Joan Vitale; Supraner, Leon, 1925-; Svennevik, Donna; Vauclaire, Gilles; Von dem Bussche, Wolf; Waters, Ray; Wright, Paula (Photographer)
- Abbott, Berenice (1898-1991)
  - Gelatin silver print, 4 x 6.5 in. mounted on a 14 x 18 mat board. Bird's eye view of Wall Street. (Offsite-box 5)
  - Gelatin silver print, 7 x 9 in. mounted on a 12 x 16 in. mat board. Statue of Leif Erikson (Offsite-box 5)
    Scope and Contents
    Gift of Ari and Helene Bousbib, 2016
- Albok, John
  - 1 gelatin silver print, 8 x 10 in., Wash Day, view of rain falling on Madison Avenue near 96th Street. Signed., 1941 (Offsite-box 1)
- Aloma, Lilyan
  - 1 gelatin silver print, 16 x 20 in., of New York City buildings including a billboard, water tower and one way sign; photograph is entitled "One Way"., 2002 (Offsite-box 5)
- Aronberg, Jacob
  - 2 gelatin silver prints, mounted, 3 1/4 x 4 3/4 in. of New York City urban youth. One shows the back window of a school bus with a bullet hole; the other is of a young girl in a sundress jumping rope down an urban sidewalk. Signed, dated and stamped by the photographer., 1978, 1987 (Offsite-box 1)
- Austen, Alice (1866-1952)
  - 13 gelatin silver prints, mounted, 4 x 5 in. or smaller, of unidentified boats. (2 folders), undated (Offsite-box 1)
- Beecher, Jim
  - 13 gelatin silver prints, 8 x 10 in., taken at the Tompkins Square Boys' Club of New York at 287 E. 10th St. in Manhattan, 1976-1986 (Offsite-box 1)
- Beller-Smith, Victoria
  - "Poor Cat" [7 boys posing with cat], undated (Offsite-box 5)
  - West 77th Street, circa 1960's-1970's (Offsite-box 5)
  - Broadway and 71st Street [Nevada Hotel demolition], circa 1970's (Offsite-box 5)
  - [Five kids 110th Street], circa 1970's (Offsite-box 5)
  - 11 contact sheets of New York City images [includes off-track betting, lower east side, Harlem, upper west side], circa 1960's-1970's (Offsite-box 5)
- Bernius, Paul
  - 1 mounted gelatin silver print, 13 1/2 x 10 1/2 in., of John Iannuzzi fleeing a fire at 572 President Street in Brooklyn, carrrying his caged parrot, Bobo; photograph is entitled Polly Wanna Cracker, Untoasted. Published newspaper clipping from the Daily News including the photograph is mounted on the verso., 1959 (Offsite-box 5)
- Binder, David
  - 2 black and white prints, 22 x 17 in., showing intravenous drug use. From the photo essay "Jon Parker.", circa 1990 (Folder OS FF Binder)
- Boughton, Alice (1865-1943)
  - 3 palladium prints; one 7 3/4 x 4 3/4 in. portrait of Henry James, one 8 1/2 x 6 5/8 in. mounted portrait of Henry James, and one 8 x 10 in. mounted portrait of an unidentified man., 1905 (Offsite-box 3)
- Bourke-White, Margaret (1904-1971)
  - 1 gelatin silver print, 6 3/4 x 4 1/2 in., portrait of S.J. Woolf, artist, signed by Bourke-White and 1 6 1/2 x 9 1/2 inch gelatin silver print of an unidentified boat, bearing the photographer's stamp., 1943, undated (Offsite-box 3)
- Burckhardt, Rudy (1914-1999)
  - 1 black and white photomechanical print on Japanese tissue paper, 8 1/4 x 6 1/4 in., of a woman walking by the Saks & Co. storefront on 34th Street in 1938, mounted with a poem by Edwin Denby, "Mid Day Crowd"., undated (Offsite-box 5)
- Cherney, Lawrence
  - 1 color photograph, 11 x 14 in., of S. Klein On the Square., [1970-1989] (Offsite-box 5)
- Cooper, Martha (1943- )
  - Olek at the Women's March, 2017 (Offsite-box 12)
    Gift of Martha Cooper, December 2017.
- Cooper, William A
  - 10 gelatin silver prints, 8 x 10 in. and smaller. Unidentified portraits., undated (Offsite-box 1)
  - 4 panoramic photographs of Catskill Mountain House and the surrounding area; 1 of an unidentified town at a river junction; 1 of Victorian houses, undated (Offsite-box 14)
    The photograph of Victorian houses is not explicitly signed or otherwise noted as a Cooper, but was found with the others in 2022 and so was left in place.
  - 5 panoramic photographs of views from Brooklyn across the East River to lower Manhattan, circa 1911 (Folder FF-1)
    None of the photos explicitly indicate they are by Cooper, but one can be found attributed to him on the Library of Congress site: [New York from Brooklyn Heights, panoramic view] at https://www.loc.gov/resource/ds.04403/. The others appear to have been taken from roughly the same spot, but at a slightly different time as different boats are on the river. The items were found together in the stacks in 2022 and were left together here.
- Cowen, Jeff
  - 5 gelatin silver prints, 11 x 14 in., of transgender sex workers in Manhattan.(2 folders), 1988 (Offsite-box 5)
- Davis, Melody D. (1959-)
  - 4 platinum/palladium prints, 12 x 10 in., of the Cathedral of St. John the Divine (Cathedral Church of St. John the Divine)., 1983 (Offsite-box 3)
- Eagle, Arnold (1909-1992)
  - 5 gelatin silver prints, 11 x 14 in. or smaller, of New York scenes including a high-angle interior of Pennsylvania Station, young Jews at Torah study, children playing in the street, and interiors of a Second Avenue elevated train station., [1930-1949] (Offsite-box 3)
- Earle, John D
  - 24 gelatin silver prints, 3 1/2" x 4 1/2", taken around 385 Hudson Avenue, Brooklyn, in the 1930s. Photographs are of children, many African American, playing street games, jumping rope and playing ball., [1930-1939] (Offsite-box 1)
- Edelman, Joyce (1945-1991)
  - 4 gelatin silver prints, 11 x 14 in., and 7 color photographs, 16 x 20 in., of New York City. Included are street scenes, skylines, aerial views showing East River bridges, and a photograph of the New York County Supreme Court entrance at 60 Centre Street. Portraits of jazz musician Doc Cheatham are included., 1988, undated (Offsite-box 8)
- Edelstein, Seymour
  - 14 gelatin silver prints, 11 x 14 in., from Edelstein's "Shopkeepers" series. Includes portraits of Jewish shopkeepers on the Lower East Side of Manhattan and in Brooklyn. Views of storefronts, signs, and shop interiors are included., 1985-1993 (Offsite-box 3)
- Fairchild, Charlotte
  - 1 gelatin silver print, 11 x 14 in., full length portrait of an unidentified boy and woman in front of exterior (garden?) door., undated (Offsite-box 3)
- Fassbender, Adolf (1884-1980)
  - Sun's Total Eclipse, 9:11 a.m., Bronx Park, N.Y.C., 1925 January 24 (Offsite-box 3)
- Feinstein, Harold
  - 7 gelatin silver prints, 11 x 14 in. of street views, a boy writing numbers with chalk on a sidewalk, a man holding a child, and snow on tree branches. All are signed, dated and numbered., 1950-1977 (Offsite-box 3)
- Feldstein, Mark (1937-)
  - 11 gelatin silver prints, 11 x 14 in. of cars and architectural details of Manhattan buildings. Photographs are high-contrast with attention to form and structure., 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3)
- Fenn, Steven
  - World Trade Center, Lower Manhattan. Chromogenic print, 16x20 in., 2001 (Offsite-box 6)
- Festa, Gerald Jude James (1981- )
  - "The Upper East Side", 1981 (Offsite-box 5)
    One black and white 20x16 photograph, showing front of the Metropolitan Museum of Art with banner for "The Eighteenth Century Woman," taken from East 82nd Street across Fifth Ave. Signed "Gerald Jude." Gift of the photographer, November 2019.
- Fink, Peter
  - 1 gelatin silver print, 10 x 6 1/2 in., mounted, of a rippled reflection of an unidentified building. Mount is signed by the photographer., undated (Offsite-box 5)
- Fournier, Frank, (1948- )
  - 4 prints, 22 x 17 in. Two photos are of people living with AIDS; two photos are of demonstrations by AIDS activists, 1985-1988 (Folder OS FF Fournier)
- Frisone, Rosemarie
  - Ferry and Statue of Liberty (going to Staten Island); Terminal Industries; Viewing Statue of Liberty (Window Reflections); Girl with dog; Docking Staten Island Side; Upper Deck (Shoe Shine with trio)., 1987-1991 (Offsite-box 3)
    6 black and white pigment prints, 11 x 14 in., all taken on the Staten Island Ferry. 4 images were a gift of Rosemarie Frisone, 2017; 2 images were purchased from the photographer, 2017
- Frost, Rosalie
  - Harris Battery # 1, Fort Tilden, 2007 (Offsite-box 5)
  - Harris Battery #2, Fort Tilden, 2007 (Offsite-box 5)
  - Dune Pond, Fort Tilden, 2007 (Offsite-box 5)
- Garn, Andrew
  - 5 color photographs, 12 x 12 in., of New York buildings, including the Guggenheim Museum, the Municipal Building, the RCA Building, 500 Fifth Avenue, and the Woolworth Building., 1981-1983 (Offsite-box 6)
- Gescheidt, Alfred
  - 4 gelatin silver prints: ship on wharf, boy on rooftop, icy watertower, firefighting at Lexington Avenue and 31st Street, circa 1960's, undated (Offsite-box 3)
- Gilbert, Lynn
  - Billie Jean King, 1978 (Offsite-box 6)
    Scope and Contents Note
    Includes one gelatin silver print, b&w, 14 x 11". Image is of King with tennis racket, seated in a locker room. Gift, Lynn Gilbert, 2017.
- Goldfarb, Anders (1954-)
  - [Young Man on Subway], 1987 January (Offsite-box 3)
    Signed. Images of graffiti on the subway car interior. Acquisition: Gift of the photographer, March 2018.
  - [Repent], 1988 January (Offsite-box 3)
    Signed. Subway car with commuters and graffiti. Acquisition: Purchase from the photographer, March 2018.
- González, Alfred
  - 14 black-and-white prints on 100% Rag Entrada [3 folders], 1978, 1983-1984 (Offsite-box 5)
    "A Ride on the 6," March 1983. [On the 6 train in the Bronx, near Castle Hill Avenue.]
    "Volkswagen Shrine," 1984. [East side of Lexington Avenue between 110th & 111th Streets.]
    "Niño en Botanica," March 1983. [East side of Lexington Avenue between 111th & 112th Streets.]
    "People," April 1983. [6 train Northbound near 86th Street.]
    "Shoot and Run," April 1983. [108th or 109th Street between 3rd and Lexington Avenues.]
    "2nd Ammendment [sic]," April 1983. [Park Avenue at about 83rd Street, west side of street.]
    "Es Tremendo," April 1983. [West side of 3rd Avenue between 115th & 116th Street.]
    "Back of the Bus," February 1983. [101 Bus, Third Avenue, near 86th Street.]
    "Lake, Boys, Volkie," April 1983. [Central Park, Conservatory Water Lake, east side near 75th Street.]
    "Fire Boat," February 1983. [South Ferry Fire House on the Battery, NY.]
    "Convenience Banking," February 1983. [Promenade of World Trade Center.]
    "Odd Couple," May 1978. [South East, Central Park Lake, The Pond, near 61st Street.]
    "Reading the Script," May 1983. [South side of 86th Street, between Lexington and Park Avenue.]
    "Fire Escape Shadows," March 1983. [East side of Lexington Avenue, between 111th and 112th Streets.]
    Purchase, Alfred González, 2019 (accession no. PPAC-2019-021).
- Gould, Keith
  - 10 digital color prints, varying sizes, from 13 x 17 1/2 in. to 13 x 19 in. from his series "Subways are for Sleeping." Each print has been numbered to correspond with it's title: 1. "yellow coat," 2. "upper east side," 3. "Michelin man," 4. "nanny," 5. "pulp fiction," 6. "terror guy," 7. "serenity," 8. "yellow scarf," 9. "yankee fan," 10. "the hood.", 2006-2007 (Offsite-box 6)
- Greenwald, Seth
  - 4 gelatin silver prints, 11 x 14 in., of the George Washington Bridge from below, a woman with flyswatter, a depiction of Jesus hung beside photograph of John F. Kennedy, and girl running beside a fountain. All are signed and numbered., 1989-1995 (Offsite-box 3)
- Hambourg, Serge (1936-)
  - 2 color photographs of a New York subway platform and a subway entrance gate. 1 gelatin silver self-portrait, 8 x 10 in., [1970-1981] (Offsite-box 1)
  - 1 color photograph, 16 x 20 in., of a subway platform at 34th Street and Seventh Avenue., ]1970-1979] (Offsite-box 8)
- Heller, Ben
  - 1 gelatin silver print, 9 1/4 x 7 1/4 in., of men playing baseball in a lot in the gas house district (East 14th Street). Stamped as an Underwood & Underwood photo by Ben Heller., [1940] (Offsite-box 1)
- Hine, Lewis
  - Making Violets, New York City. Gelatin silver print, 4 5/8in. x 6 5/8in., 1912 (Offsite-box 1)
- Hofer, Evelyn
  - 1 gelatin silver print, 8 x 10 in., of the World Trade Center under construction., [1966-1970] (Offsite-box 1)
- Hoffman, Steve
  - "Boys in the Hallway," Angels in the Church," Girls on the Couch," "Saturday Morning at the Beauty Parlor", undated (Offsite-box 3)
    4 black and white photographs, 11 x 14". Signed by photographer. Purchase from the photographer, 2008.
- Jackson, William Henry (1843-1942)
  - 3 albumen photographs, approx. 16 x 20 in., of the Hudson River from various locations in New York State., [ca. 1890] (Offsite-box 8)
- Johnston, Frances Benjamin (1864-1952)
  - 1 gelatin silver print, 11 x 13 1/2 in., mounted, of 9 wives of the United States Cabinet, including Mrs. Daniel Scott Lamont(wife of the Secretary of War)., 1897 (Offsite-box 6)
- Kalmanoff, Raphael J.
  - 6 toned gelatin silver prints, 11 x 14 in., of the Coney Island Gyroscope and Steeplechase, New York street scenes, and an elevated railroad. All are signed., [1940-1949] (Offsite-box 3)
- Katvan, Rivka, 1981
  One photograph used in the exhibition "Celebrating Bill Cunningham" shown at New-York Historical Society from June 8 to September 9, 2018. Loaned for the exhibition, the photo was donated by the photographer afterward. Archival quality digital print from an original 35mm negative. Image: 14 x 9-7/16 in. Sheet: 22 x 17 in. added to the Photographer File collection in May 2019.
  - "Bill Cunningham sewing tulle into wedding dress bodice for Julie Schafler", 1981 March 23 (Offsite-box 8)
- Katz, Bruce, 2012
  - City Limits (post Sandy) Orchard Beach, Bronx inkjet print on Hahnmuhle paper 22"x17", 2012 (Offsite-box 8)
  - City Limits (post Sandy) Riis Park, Queens inkjet print on Hahnmuhle paper 22"x17", 2012 (Offsite-box 8)
- Kent, Karen
  - 1 color photograph, 11 x 14 in., of the South Street seaport., 1984 (Offsite-box 6)
- Leifer, Martin (1916- )
  - 65 gelatin silver prints, 8 x 10 in. or smaller, straightforward architectural photographs of locations in Manhattan, Brooklyn, and Governors Island, including Coney Island, the Brooklyn Navy Yard, and Governors Island residences. (4 folders), 1968, 1972 (Offsite-box 1)
  - 1 gelatin silver print, 6 x 9 1/2 in., mounted, of St. Paul's Chapel with the Western Union Building., undated (Offsite-box 6)
- LeVay, Gina
  - 5 Archival pigment prints of Sandhogs working in City Water Tunnel #3, Manhattan Sect, 2004-2007 (Offsite-box 9)
- Littlejohn, Ann
  - 1 color photograph, 11 x 14 in., of New York Mayor David Dinkins., 1990 (Offsite-box 3)
- Lyon, Danny (1942-)
  - 1 gelatin silver print, 7 1/2 x 7 1/2 in., of the interior of 88 Gold Street. [Plate 33 from the book "The Destruction of Lower Manhattan" (1969).] Signed, stamped, numbered, and dated on the verso., 1967 (Offsite-box 6)
- Mackey, Chris
  - 27 gelatin silver prints, 7 x 10 in., of street scenes and shop windows on the Lower East Side of Manhattan, primarily on Ludlow and Orchard Streets. (2 folders), [1970-1983] (Offsite-box 2)
- McGovern, Thomas
  - 2 black and white prints of tattoo artist Mike Bakaty and his clients at his studio at 295 Bowery., ca.1988-1991 (Offsite-box 6)
    Gift of Thomas McGovern, 2016.
- Merrill, Larry
  - Bethesda Terra [bride being photographed] (chromogenic print from film negative), 2005 (Folder OS FF Merrill)
  - Madison Avenue (digital print on cotton rag paper using pigmented ink), 2008 (Folder OS FF Merrill)
- Meyers, William (1938-)
  - 1 gelatin silver print, Hunts Point Market, Bronx, 1999 November 17 (Offsite-box 2)
- Meyerhoff, Neil (1949-)
  - 5 color photographs, 11 x 14 in., of New York street life, often with reflections in shop windows., 1989-1990 (Offsite-box 4)
- Mikhailovich, Alexander
  - 1 gelatin silver print, 8 1/2 x 5 1/2 in., is a self portrait. 16 photomechanical views, 5 x 7 in., of New York City, including aerial views., [1990] (Offsite-box 2)